technolism.com 2012-10-14

# Privacy Policy for Technolism.com

Technolism (www.technolism.com) is strongly committed to working towards the privacy of its readers and keep your personal information secure. At [Technolism.com](http://www.technolism.com/), the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by [Technolism](http://www.technolism.com/) and how it is used.

Your email address is saved with our feed manager [Feedburner](http://www.feedburner.com/). You can [get the new posts directly in your inbox](http://www.feedburner.com/fb/a/mailverify?uri=Technolism&loc=en_US) and we will also keep you updated on any developments and the new postings on this blog. You can also at anytime choose to unsubscribe.

We use third-party advertising companies ([Google AdSense](https://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?answer=9712&topic=8421&sourceid=aso&subid=ww-ww-et-asui&medium=link)) to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies use information  **(not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number)** about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

This Privacy Policy applies exclusively to information practices related to our website. Although this website contains links to other websites and lists the views expressed there, please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those, or any other sites. If you follow a link to another website you should carefully read their privacy policy.

###  **Personal Information Collected on this Website**

 ****No personally-identifiable information is collected on this website from  consumers that browse the website for information or use the opt-out service.

The only personally-identifiable information collected on this website is gathered on our “[Contact Us](http://www.technolism.com/contact-technolism "Contact Us")” page, where fields are provided so that you can provide your name, email address and other contact information. We collect this information so that we can respond to the comments that you send to us via that form.

[Technolism](http://www.technolism.com/) is the sole owner of all information collected on this site. Technolism will not rent, sell or share any personally-identifiable information about you with third parties for any reason except when required to assist in resolving an issue you raise with us or as required by law.

We do not merge any of the personally-identifiable information collected via our [contact form](http://www.technolism.com/contact-technolism "contact form") with other anonymous data collected on our website.

###  **Log Files**

 ****Like many other Web sites,[Technolism](http://www.technolism.com/contact-technolism) makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.  
****

### **Anonymous Information Collected on this Website**

 ****We record anonymous data such as traffic logs, number of visits or clicks on a given page, pages viewed or links to our site, using ([Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/support/analytics/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=55591)). We use IP addresses and cookies for gathering website statistics. ****

We aggregate this anonymous data as part of managing, maintaining and reporting on use of our website. We do not rent, sell or share any anonymous data collected on this website with third parties for marketing purposes. None of this anonymous data is linked to personally-identifiable information and we make no attempt to  link IP addresses to the individuals who visit this site.

###  **Cookies and Web Beacons**

 ****[Technolism](http://www.technolism.com/) does use cookies to store information about visitor’s preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

Cookies are small chunks of data created by a web server, delivered through a web browser, and stored on your computer. They provide a means for websites that you visit to keep track of your online patterns and preferences, as well as identify you as a return visitor. Cookies make the personalization of your web experiences possible, so that you do not need to re-enter your information from scratch upon each visit to a given website.  **No personally-identifiable information is collected by or linked to any of the cookies delivered on our site.**

You have the ability to manage the use of cookies on your computer using controls in your web-browser. To learn more about how to manage cookies, visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

###  **DoubleClick DART Cookie**

Specifically, for Google’s advertising Program  **AdSense** , users please take note of the following:

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on [Technolism](http://www.technolism.com/).
  * Google’s use of the  **DART cookie** enables it to serve ads to the users based on their visit to this site and other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).
  * Please read [Privacy Policy for Google ads](http://www.google.com/privacy_cookies.html) as well as the [DoubleClick Privacy Policy](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/).

The third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on Technolism send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

Technolism has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. Technolism’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

###  **Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

Technolism is a new Blog; we are still in the growing phase. As our organization, membership and services evolve, this Privacy Policy may be revised to reflect those changes, where applicable. We therefore reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy at any time, for any reason. Users are encouraged to check our site frequently to review the current Privacy Policy in effect.

###  **Questions?**

 ****Please  [contact us](http://www.technolism.com/contact-technolism) with any questions about this website [Privacy Policy](http://www.technolism.com/about/technolism-privacy-policy).
